three things I like about the Rogue
Olympic weightlifting barbell is the
super grippy knurling the smooth rate of
spin on the loading sleeves and the fact
that it has a tensile strength rating of
215 000 PSI I've been using this barbell
for all of my Olympic lifts lately so
let's go ahead and talk about all of my
findings
yo what's up everybody it's Jake back in
the barbing garage gym and for today's
video I've got the Rogue Olympic
weightlifting barbell info review in
this video I'm going to take you through
everything you need to know about this
barbell and the price and the features
some pros and cons and of course who
should or maybe should not add this to
their home gym but before I get going
with any of that I gotta let you in on a
little secret right here we have
reviewed a ton of barbells on barbin.com
so if you want to browse our best list
all you got to do is search bar Bend
best barbells and you can find out for
yourself which one takes home that
number one spot
okay so what do I like about this
barbell well first and foremost it has a
really respectable tensile strength
rating of 215
000 PSI now tinsel strength is going to
essentially determine how strong a
barbell is and really tell you how much
punishment it can go through before it
begins to bend on you now since this
rating is pretty close to that Max
number of around 230 maybe even 235 000
PSI you're really going to be able to
put this barbell through the ringer in
the gym trust me since this is in fact
an Olympic barbell you know the spin on
the loading sleeves is huge when it
comes to those Olympic lifts such as a
power clean and I gotta say the spin on
these loading sleeves right here is
arguably the smoothest I've ever felt on
a barbell so that's really nice I also
really like the knurling right here
super grippy it's not too abrasive
though I mean that's obviously really
crucial because you want to have a good
grip when you're doing those Olympic
lifts but not to the point where it's
going to tear your hands up and that's
not going to happen here with this
barbell and speaking of knurling you do
have a center knurling right here and
this isn't something that I typically
like but you know since this really
isn't that abrasive right here and it
really just provides you a little bit
extra grip as you're going to do that
power clean and you know the barbell
sticking to your chest I personally
really like that and since it's also
approved by the iwf it's so official all
it needs is a whistle
[Music]
okay so let's talk about a couple issues
you may run into with this barbell now
obviously it's coming from Rogue so it's
going to be pretty expensive I have the
zinc version this is right around 560
dollars and that's before taxes now
shipping is free so that's nice but
you're basically gonna be spending
around 600 just on this barbell and
considering it's a specialty bar and you
know it's not that versatile since you
can't really do power lifting with it I
don't really think you want to do that
because the knurling you know is not as
abrasive as a power lifting bar would be
or even some of those multi-purpose bars
like the Rogue Ohio bar is so you know
because of that you know there's
probably not a ton of people who are
going to be jumping at the bit going by
this barbell because odds are you only
looking to have one barbell in your
garage gym and you want one that is as
highly versatile as possible and once
again you know this is the zinc version
of this bar now there's a couple other
versions out there for you to purchase
I'll talk about that in just a second
but this version specifically it's not
going to be the best for somebody who's
not keeping all their gear you know
stashed in a climate controlled
environment so luckily I have AC in this
garage now but you know zinc is more
prone to rust and corrosion forming than
what a stainless steel bar or even a
cerakote bar would be so definitely keep
that in mind as well
all right so let's talk some cash money
now once again this is the zinc version
of this barbell and it's listed right
around 560 dollars before taxes now
there's also a cerakote version that's
listed around 605 dollars before taxes
there's also a stainless steel version
of this bar that's going to come stock
with chrome sleeves you can swap it out
for stainless steel now that one's
starting at 620 bucks but if you do in
fact want those stainless steel sleeves
for more protection from rust and
corrosion that's going to be an
additional 80 or so you know once you
tack on shipping with that you're
spending over 700 just on that stainless
steel barbell but the grip from it might
be worth it there's also a 25 millimeter
version for you to purchase as well
which is available for right around 550
bucks or so now it is worth mentioning
that this zinc version right here is the
only one that comes with that Center
knurling so definitely keep that in mind
now if you don't want to Shell out 600
up front you know maybe even 700 if you
go with that stainless steel with the
stainless steel sleeves you know you can
definitely Finance this barbell there's
two different options for you to work
with you can use a firm or you can use
paylater from PayPal now a firm is going
to run a credit score check on you it's
not going to affect your score but it is
going to determine how much you pay and
then pay later has a couple different
options for you to work with as well you
can pay over 24 months or you can make
four interest-free payments so
definitely just check out those options
and see what works best for you now
compared to the rest of the market
there's a lot of Cheaper Olympic
barbells out there for you to purchase
there's also a lot of multi-purpose bars
as well all that are also cheaper so you
know unless you're really having an
emphasis on Olympic lifting maybe that's
the only style of lifting that you
really do I would definitely recommend
checking out those other options because
they're probably just as strong you know
they're more versatile and you're going
to save a couple hundred dollars but if
I'm playing Devil's Advocate you know
this is a really sound barbell and when
it comes to your Olympic lifting needs
this is likely the only Olympic style
bar that you're ever going to need to
purchase
[Music]
okay so let's talk about the build now
and some features with this Olympic
lifting barbell now once again this is
the zinc version of this bar from end to
end it's fully zinc it's also available
in cerakote and stainless steel if you
would prefer you know that hover over a
zinc coated barbell this is the 20
kilogram version of this bar it's 86.6
inches in length with 16.2 inch loading
sleeves now there's also a 25 millimeter
bar that's referring to the diameter of
course that's going to be 79 inches
inches in length and it's going to have
12 and a half inch loading sleeves now I
gotta say for a zinc barbell the
knurling right here is awesome so those
zinc bars you know because of that
coating can tend to be a little less
grippy than a stainless steel bar can be
I gotta say you know Rogue definitely
did their homework with this barbell and
they just knocked it out of the park
it's definitely grippy but it's not too
abrasive where it's going to tear your
hands up as you're going to do a power
clean so so that's a really nice touch
the center knurling right here is also
going to be really nice in terms of
keeping that bar on your chest and
adding a little bit of traction as you
go to do those power cleans and really
just make it stick right there for you
this also has a tinsel strength rating
of 215 000 PSI and my personal opinion I
think that is more than enough for an
Olympic style lift now since this is an
elliptic lifting bar you know once again
it's approved by the iwf for
competitions which is really cool you're
only going to have one set of neural
markings right here and those are set of
course by the iwf so it's really nice
you know you know exactly where to put
your hands as you're going to do you
know a wide grip Style version of those
lists which is really cool now you do
have a pair of five needle bearings in
both of the sleeves it's going to really
allow you to get a really solid rate of
Spin and the sleeves themselves are
actually friction welded together and
that's done by applying heat and
pressure and spinning the two together
all at one time it's where it's really
just one single piece now a lot of
barbells out there let's talk about the
Rogue Ohio bar you know you can take
those sleeves off and re-lubricate them
and make sure everything spins nicely
well you can't do that with these
sleeves right here but I don't think
that's really something you're going to
have to worry about I've I've felt as if
they're pretty solid and they're going
to stay solid for a really long time the
sleeves also have a really solid Groove
pattern right here and if you don't
really know what those are for it's
really just going to assist you in terms
of keeping your plates in their original
placement obviously you don't want them
towards the end of the sleeve you want
them as close to you and your hands
really as possible now you definitely
need to toss some weight collars on here
just to help you out and for your own
safety but I'm really impressed by these
grooves on these loading sleeves and
let's talk about the zinc one more time
yeah it is going to provide some
protection from rust and corrosion but
you know if you're not in a climate
controlled environment this is not going
to be the optimal choice for you
definitely want to take a hard look at
that stainless steel or the cerakote
versions because those are going to be
you know the go-to with stainless steel
definitely raining Supreme so definitely
keep that in mind you know you'll
probably have to clean this more so than
you would if it was stainless steel but
as long as you do clean it every once in
a while I don't think you'll have any
problems whatsoever
[Applause]
[Music]
all right you know what time it is it's
time for the walk around so let's go
ahead and look at these loading sleeves
right here you know once again it's
stamped it's so official that all it
needs is a whistle it's approved by the
iwf4 weightlifting competition so it's
really nice you know if you're a
competitor this could be a really nice
addition to your home gym I really like
these grooves right here on the loading
sleeves they're pretty impressive to me
and it does a really good job of keeping
your weight plates in their original
placement but I definitely still
recommend I'm always going to use some
weight collars for your own protection
now these also have a really nice rate
of spin thanks to the five needle
bearings it's gonna be really nice as
you go to do those Olympic style lifts
and really help that bar you know twist
and turn in your hands and really get
that the weight up let's move further on
down the line now I'm really impressed
with this knurling right here especially
since this is a zinc barbell now because
of that zinc coating a lot of times you
know zinc bars they're not as grippy as
a stainless steel bar is and honestly
I knew I was getting a zinc bar but I
kind of thought it was stainless steel
when I first put my hands on it because
the grip felt that good in my opinion
now once again this is that iwf bar it's
an Olympic Bar so you only have one set
of neural markings and that's really
going to be nice as you got to do those
lifts once again this is a zinc bar it's
not going to be the optimal choice in
terms of rust and Corrosion Protection
luckily there is a cerakote and a
stainless steel version if you're ever
worried about that you don't really want
to clean the bar all that much and
lastly you do have a center knurling
right here
I'm typically not too crazy about Center
nerlings but you know this really isn't
abrasive it's kind of just there to give
you a little bit more traction and
really help that bar stick to your chest
and yeah I gotta say
in my time using it I've definitely been
able to tell the difference
[Music]
okay so let's talk about the people who
should purchase this barbell well if
you're an Olympic lifter or you're a
crossfitter you know this bar is perfect
for that style of lift obviously it is
an Olympic Bar and you know if you do
have a main focus on that style of lift
then I don't know why you wouldn't want
to consider this barbell it has a
tensile strength rating of 215 000 PSI
which I think is going to be more than
enough for most people out there
watching and lastly it is approved by
the iwf once again so if you're a
competitor I think you know you're gonna
love this barbell
foreign
okay so who should not purchase this
barbell well this is a specialty bar
it's designed for Olympic lifting
obviously but also CrossFit as well so
it's you know not really meant to be
used for any power lifting I'm sure you
could if you really wanted to but it's
really not what it's meant for by any
means necessary so if you're not pretty
much only doing those two style of lifts
I would definitely suggest checking out
some multi-purpose bars that can really
handle everything once again this is the
zinc version of this bar so if you're
not in a climate controlled environment
you definitely want to check out the
stainless steel or the cerakote versions
now those are going to cost you more
money but it might be worth it you know
because of longevity and let's talk
about money again you know this is
expensive it's going to be at least
around 600 and you know if you're on a
tight budget you don't want to spend
that much money on just a barbell
once again I think you should check out
some cheaper Olympic bars or maybe even
just go for a multi-purpose bar like I
just said and it's going to be able to
handle everything and save you some
money as well that's about all I got for
y'all today on the Rogue Olympic
weightlifting barbell honestly it was
love at first sight for me and this
barbell the knurling is awesome the
sleeves spin at a really high rate and
it has a really respectable tinsel
strength rating of 215 000 PSI just
remember this is the zinc version of
this bar and you know if you're not in a
climate controlled environment then you
probably gonna have to spend more money
on an already expensive barbell just to
go for that stainless steel version
thanks for hanging out with me everybody
I hope this video was really helpful and
that I was able to break down everything
you need to know about this barbell as
always stay posted for my next review
but for now you know what you should do
well I think you should go over to
barbin.com and read more about this
barbell all you gotta do is search
barvin Rogue Olympic weightlifting bar
review and you'll find all the details
and everything I discussed here today
I'll see y'all next time
[Music]